Hi my name is Lauren and today I am here to discuss how to brush your hair.
Brushing your hair has a few different advantages.
Number one it can help you to create the style that you would like and the style that you are looking to achieve.
It also increases the blood circulation to your brain which nourishes your papilla.
Once the blood circulation actually increases towards your brain and towards your scalp your nutrients, your papilla which is where the base of your hair follicle is going to grab nutrients out of your bloodstream and help nourish your hair so it is a very good thing to be in the habit of brushing your hair on a regular basis.
The easiest way to brush your hair especially if your hair is rather knotted is to start at the bottom of the end of the shaft and work your way up.
If you use a Boar's Head bristle then it will also help promote smoothness in your hair and it will help maintain frizz.
Plastic bristles will also help get all of those knots out because it has a bit of a better grab to it.
So again you are going to start at the end of your hair shaft and you are going to work your way up towards your root.
Once you get towards your root you can then do a few really good brush strokes in order to increase that circulation and have more blood flow go up to your scalp and that is how to brush your hair.